PERSONAL INFORMATION

ROUCHAN AL HELO



Erbil, Iraq



+9647507764918

x rochanalhelo87@gmail.com

Sex Female | Date of birth 15/09/1987 | Nationality Syrian

I am a diplomatic person, who works with persistence, willingness and Enthusiasm to exceed guest's

I do believe that with a positive attitude, team work and targeted Planning I can obtain the objectives.

OBJECTIVES

Looking for a vacancy in your reputable company where I can use my Current experience, get new knowledge, and improve my skills.

SPECIAL KNOWLEDGE

Reduce the cost of companies without compromising the quality by using new methods and tools. Help the companies to increase profitability and the quality, services, Analyse the present services and do research using various methods to constantly improve the company standards.

WORK EXPERIENCE

International Organization for Migration IOM - UN- MSA (2017) Current Job

Responsibilities / Achievements:

- Accurately record data for visa application processing and/or integrity analysis;
- Open and process mail;
- Assemble and maintain file records and ensure data integrity in electronic systems;
- Answer client inquiries, including telephone and email inquiries relating to visa requirements;
- Assess basic visa application criteria and make recommendations to decision-makers; and
- Undertake verification checks of documentation lodged by visa applicants, including telephone checks, sending correspondence and some site visits throughout India, as required.

Gravity Communication Agency – Account Manager (2016-2017)

Responsibilities / Achievements:

- Provides strategic recommendations and manages all Company/Agency resources to ensure the Client's marketing
- Responsible for the overall service and profitability of assigned accounts, typically reports to the CEO.
- Meeting and liaising with clients to discuss and identify their advertising requirements;
- Working with agency colleagues to devise an advertising campaign that meets the client's brief and budget.
- Presenting, alongside agency colleagues, the campaign ideas and budget to the client.
- Working with the account executive to brief media, creative and research staff, and assisting with the formulation of marketing strategies.
- Liaising with, and acting as the link between, the client and advertising agency by maintaining regular Contact with both, ensuring that communication flows effectively.
- Negotiating with clients and agency staff about the details of campaigns.
- Presenting creative work to clients for approval or modification.
- Monitoring the effectiveness of campaigns.
- Undertaking administration tasks.
- Arranging and attending meetings.
- Making 'pitches', along with other agency staff, to try to win new business for the agency.

STARWOOD Hotels & Resorts - Sales Manager (2014-2016)

Responsibilities / Achievements:

- Whilst building the Division, I obtained many international and local clients, whilst achieving the monthly targets and gaining bonuses for myself and my team.
- Engaging new clients included many renowned international Oil companies.
- Promoting Sheraton Hotel Duhok, I contacted and liaised with many advertising companies from Kurdistan, Jordan
 and Turkey in order to source a suitable agency to assist with advertising and promoting of Sheraton Hotel Duhok.
- Organizing and leading a team of sales representatives, with a view to achieving a set of goals for sales for the whole team
- Seeting goals and follow up their implementation.
- Recruitment and training of sales staff, and the allocation of areas for sales representatives.
- Preparing marketing calendar and plan for the year.
- Compilation and analysis of sales figures, and deal directly with key customers, and gather customer feedback and
 market research, And develop sales strategies and goal-setting, and monitoring the performance of the team and
 motivate them to reach the goals. And report to managers responsible.

SARDAR GROUP - Assistant Marketing Manager (2012 - 2014)

Responsibilities / Achievements:

- Responsible for the preparation and the development of marketing plans and sales and organize the selling activity.
- Monitoring and evaluation of the activities of sales and marketing, and the development of own sales management
 operational plan in order to serve the strategic plan, and ensure the implementation of this plan by ensuring the
 conduct of marketing and sales management business.
- Responsible for determining need section of the sales representatives, marketing and distribution, qualifications and needs, training and rehabilitation, and estimate the marketing department's budget, raising the company's market share in target markets to achieve competitive advantage.
- High capabilities in the development and draw the plans and policies of marketing and sales.

Alfuttaim Group, Arab orient Insurance Co. Dubai Head office - Insurance Consultant (2011 - 2012)

As an insurance consultant I used mathematical and statistical concepts to determine probability and assess risks.

- Evaluating employee's performance by having one on one self-evaluation session on a regular basis.
- Writing detailed reports and letters.
- Applying a range of techniques to resolve different types of business problems.
- Working with professionals to develop systems that ensure compliance with the requirements of regulatory bodies.
- Participating in management meetings and meeting deadlines set by the company's regulations and guidelines.
- Gather and share extensive knowledge on insurance
- Collaborating with a range of colleagues.
- Selecting and using IT software to manage data.
- Researching current developments in the business and financial worlds.

SALEH KAMEL GROUP – Sales Supervisor (2005 – 2010)

I commenced my career at Promo ART a Sales Officer. In September 2007 I was promoted as an as sales Supervisor, which portrays my commitment to any given responsibility and job whilst proving the confidence required to grow within a company in a short span of time.

Duties & responsibilities:

- Supervise the employee,
- Train them and help them solving the current and the upcoming problems
- Throughout the working hours.
- Organizing logistics & accommodation for VIP guests.
- Prepare a daily sales report to be sent to the headquarters in Dubai,
- As well as helping put the monthly report with sales plan.
- Coordinate the appointments with the company's managers
- Make sure that all the messages are taken and passed to the right person
- Communicate with my colleagues to have a smooth operation.

PROMO 7 GROUP - Assistant Team Leader (2004 - 2005)

Responsibilities / Achievements:

- As an Assistant Team Leader, managing a successful team of 15 Sales Officers.
 Provide Administrative to my team.
- Answering Customer's queries or routing the Customers to the correct department.
- Achieving the monthly targets set by the Management on a daily basis.
- Creating an extensive database of clients throughout the Northern Emirates, and of the Levant.
- As a member of the organizing committee, liaison with media personnel, celebrity managers, government and private institutions in order to organize concerts and products launches in Dubai.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Bachelor Degree (2004 - 2008)

<u>Tishreen University, Lattakia</u> (Business Administration, Banking & Insurance)

TRAINING CERTIFICATE

- Diplomas from QUSET Company 2006 2008
- Two Diplomas on Customers` Services DUBAI
- Diploma on Effective leadership _ EGYPT
- Diploma on sales Experiences SYRIA
- Diploma on training the trainer JORDAN
- In 2008 I was an employee year of the company in the ART

PERSONAL SKILLS

Mother tongue(s) ARABIC

Other language(s) English

Communication skills

I am confident that my organized, methodical and conscientious approach to work together with my excellent verbal and written communication skills, which have been compressed by my employment, will be an asset to your organization.

My intelligence and ability to apply initiatives in any given situation, together with my creativeness and interpersonal skills surpass any of my peers.

Good communication skills as a part of working in the customer service Good solving problems skills as a part of working in the customer service

Field and dealing with angry difficult customers

Excellent analysing, able to handle sensitive and critical situations.

Employee of year in 2008

Computer skills

Computer literate with knowledge in MS Office, Outlook and Internet Explorer, with typing skills excellent administration skills gained from my previous experience

Driving licence References International certificate Available upon request